Md.Khaled Hossain

H#457/1, Ward-3, Ashkona Medical Road, Ashkona, Dakshin Khan, Dhaka-1230.

E-mail: md.khaled.eee@gmail.com
https://github.com/khaled-hossain-code
https://www.linkedin.com/in/khaled-hossain-code

Mobile: +8801944665975.



Objective

My goal is to bring experience, maturity, focus, knowledge, and a healthy amount of hubris to my job in order to tackle both technological and personal challenges.

I am passionate about doing things right and doing them quickly. These are not antithetical; a proper knowledge of principles, action in the face of ambiguity, and diplomacy to coax the best from all can nurture a self-organized software team.

Employment history

Kutumbita

Sr Software Engineer | November 2018 - Present

DevoTech Technology Park Ltd, Plot 11, Gulshan - 2, Dhaka.

Web: https://www.kutumbita.com

Kutumbita is a startup company in HR solution platform. This platform streamlines communication and increases employee engagement between different levels of a factory.

Chatbot Service

Chatbot service is the core product of Kutumbita. This service consists of different types of bots like survey bot, issue bot, leave bot. App users communicates with these bots real time in different languages and non app users communicates via sms and whatsApp.

Technologies: Typescript, Node.js, Express, Socket.io, Redis, Io-dash, Async, mocha, sinon, chai, joi, morgan, winston, moment.

Functioned as one of the owner of this service.

• Implement different types of bots and execute actions through different micro services.

Message Hub

Message hub is the gateway of all third-party messaging platform. This service is responsible to maintain the session for SMS type conversation through twilio or infobip. And also third-party messaging platforms like whatsApp, facebook etc. This service is responsible to understand user's response through nlp and forward to chatbot service.

Technologies: Typescript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Graphql, ElasticSearch, Redis, lo-dash, i18n-nodejs, string-similarity, unidecode etc.

- Functioned as one of the owner of this service.
 - Integrate different types of sms gateway for different countries.
 - Integrate third-party messengers like whatsApp.
 - Provide analytics data using ElasticSearch.

Kutumbita Web

Kutumbita web is a SPA geared towards managers to see analytics and issue submitted by workers.

Technologies: ReactJS, React-router, Redux, redux-thunk, viser-react, axios, lodash, antd, jwt, Cypressjs, enzyme etc.

- Functioned as Sr Front-end developer.
 - Bootstrap scalable react project.
 - Implement filters and searches.
 - Design redux stores.

Other services contributed in like api-gateway-web, api-gateway-mobile, super-admindashboard, Bot Logger etc.

NewsCred

Software Engineer | January 2017 – October 2018 Green Grandeur, Plot 58/E, Banani, Dhaka.

Web: https://www.newscred.com

NewsCred is the global leader in enterprise content marketing. They are the leading content marketing sass company in the world. Their primary products are license content and CMP (content marketing platform). Our team is the owner of heart of CMP, Idea lab & Pitch manager. We were responsible to understand user needs, suggest them solution and implement the right solution which will solve user's problem.

Content Marketing Platform (CMP)

CMP is the core product of NewsCred. It is a complete solution for content search, produce, manage, store, collaborate, schedule and publish. It is a micro service app. Other primary services are publishing service, channel service, authentication service, pitch manager, idea lab etc.

Technologies: Angularjs, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Socket.io, Io-dash, Async, passport, redis, mocha, sinon, chai.

- Functioned as software engineer for this project
 - Deconstructed client needs into user software requirements specification.
 - Formulated and documented technical architecture, components, and strategies for mitigating technical challenges.
 - Worked closely with customer's development team to identify APIs, define data schemas, and document workflows, business requirements, and domain knowledge.

Pitch Manager

This is the service which helps user to request for content and collaborate with writers for original content. This service maintains creating, collaborate, approve of pitch and start a workflow from the approved pitch.

Technologies: Flask, MySQL, Pytest, SQLAlchemy, requests.

- Acted as owner of this portion of cmp.
 - Implement different new features of pitch manager. Archive pitch & pitch requests, Different level of permissions, sorting, filtering pitch & pitch requests etc.
 - Maintain, bug fixing and UI development of pitch manager.

Idea Lab

This is the service which helps user to find competitor analysis info. This also shows which keywords are doing well in SEO for their hub. Show key results in charts.

Technologies: Flask-restplus, MySQL, Pytest, SQLAlchemy, redis, chartjs.

- · Acted as contributor in this service.
 - Font-end development of idea lab.
 - Create charts in font-end.

Website Widget

Website widget serves widget to client's hub which shows intelligently recommended articles.

Technologies: NodeJS, Express, AWS Athena, AWS lambda@edge, bluebird, bunyan, redis, sequelize, MySQL, mocha, chai, sinon, nock, pm2.

- Acted as contributor in this service.
 - Bootstrapped this service, adding logger, write build script.
 - Collect event from client's hub using cloud-front, lambda@edge.
 - Aggregate & display result of events using aws Athena.
 - Create CTA of clients hub which will be served by this widget.

Support Dashboard

This is an internal tool used to do different type of client custom request, on boarding etc.

Technologies: Django, Angularjs, celery, MySQL, redis.

- Acted as developer in this tool.
 - Automated different client requests into this dashboard.
 - Run different scripts using celery.

Intelligent Design & Dynamics Ltd., | http://www.iddbd.net Embedded System & Nodejs Developer | November 2015 – Dec 2016 Responsibilities: - My core responsibility is to design medical real-time solutions, Circuit design and programming. My other responsibilities are Server side programming, socket programming, NoSQL database programming. As a project lead I have to do product packaging & production management works also.

Web Application for Nurse Call System

Nurse call system is a networked online calling system for patients. Patients can call nurse from their bed by pendant, nurse can call for emergency or bluecode help by presence button. Nurse can request for room cleanup and other services by the system. Management can see reports of nurse response time, maximum work load time, average calls etc. Nurse can see calls in web app real-time.

Technologies: Node.js, Express, EJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Socket.io, Iodash, Async, SendGrid, body-parser, Morgan, bootstrap, jQuery, pm2, git.

- Functioned as technical lead for this project and backend developer
 - Deconstructed client needs into user software requirements specification.
 - Formulated and documented technical architecture, components, and strategies for mitigating technical challenges.
 - Worked closely with customer's development team to identify APIs, define data schemas, and document workflows, business requirements, and domain knowledge.
- Designed the Node.js backend MVC structure
 - Restructuring Express framework as MVC architecture.
 - Creating CRUD operation APIs & routing in express.
- Database Schema design & database query
 - Designed Schema using Mongoose library.
 - API related queries were created using MongoDB query.
 - If database crashed App will send email notification.
- Real-Time communication between Server & Client

- Using socket.io library real-time communication between client & server was established.
- Event-driven communication between server & client.
- Real-time data pushed to client without any HTTP/Ajax request from client.

Bangladesh Automation Technologies | http://batbd.net/

Embedded System Engineer | July 2014 – October 2015

Responsibilities: - Lecture on micro-controller, embedded system design, Circuit design and programming, Circuit debugging and code debugging.

Robotics Bangladesh | http://store.roboticsbd.com/

Embedded System Engineer | January 2013 - June 2014

Responsibilities: - Lecture on micro-controller, embedded system design, different projects, Circuit design and programming, Circuit debugging and code debugging.

Academic Background

Name of Institution	Degree	Dept.	Year	CGPA
Rajuk Uttara Model School & College	S.S.C	Science	2001-2003	5
Notre Dame college	H.S.C	Science	2003-2005	4.7
American International University Bangladesh	B.Sc.	EEE	2007-2011	3.4
Military Institution of Science & Technology	M.Sc.	EECE	2015	3.2

International Journal Publications

 Md. Sabbir, Sumit Bhattacharyya and Md. Khaled Hossain, "Differential Drive adaptive Proportional-Integral-Derivative (PID) controlled Mobile Robot Speed Synchronization" International Journal of Computer Applications , November 2014.

- M2M: GSM Network for Robots using DTMF in Global Journal of Researches in Engineering. Electrical and Electronics Engineering (U.S.A). Volume-13, Issue 10
- GSM based wireless sensor network to measure global warming, humidity & CO₂. International Journal of Computer Applications (U.S.A).
- 28 Digital Logic Design Operations by One Microcontroller. International Journal of Emerging Technology and Advanced Engineering. Volume 3, Issue 6, June 2013
- Fault Analysis and Electrical Protection of Distribution Transformers. Volume 14 Issue 3 Version 1.0 Year 2014. Global Journal of Researches in Engineering: Electrical and Electronics Engineering.
- Detection of Car Pre-crash with human, avoidance system & localizing through GSM. International Journal of Scientific and Research Publications(Canada)
- Software Defined 8, 16 & 24 Bit Digital Logic Design by One Microcontroller in Engineering. Electrical and Electronics Engineering (U.S.A). Volume-13, Issue 10

Personal Details

Permanent Address : A.B.A Nir Nirjhan, Ashkona, Dhaka.

Email : md.khaled.eee@gmail.com

Mob : 01944665975 Date of Birth : 04 Oct, 1987.

References

Imran M Yousuf Mr. Rinku Basak

VP of Engineering at NewsCred

Assistant Professor

Green Grandeur, Plot 58/E, Banani,

Graduate Head, EEE Department

American International University

Bangladesh

Mob:- +8801712010876

Dhaka.

Email:- Imran.yousuf@newscred.com